[
 {
      "question":"Which of the following committee was responsible to register every birth and death in Mauryan administration?",
      "optionA":"Vital Statistics",
      "optionB":"Foreigners",
      "optionC":"Home Affairs",
      "optionD":"Tax Collection",
      "correctAns":"Vital Statistics"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following was the head of the board of infantry in Mauryan administration?",
      "optionA":"Padadhyaksha",
      "optionB":"Rathadhyaksha",
      "optionC":"Asvadhyaksha",
      "optionD":"Hastyadhyaksha",
      "correctAns":"Padadhyaksha"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following refers to the name of the villages exempted from paying tax?",
      "optionA":"Pariharaka",
      "optionB":"Ayudhiya",
      "optionC":"Kupya",
      "optionD":"Nagar",
      "correctAns":"Pariharaka"
   },
   {
      "question":"The achievements of Gautamiputra Satkarni were described and eulogised after his death in which of the following inscriptions?",
      "optionA":"Junagarh Inscription",
      "optionB":"Naneghat Inscription",
      "optionC":"Nashik Inscription",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Nashik Inscription"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following started the Gupta era?",
      "optionA":"Chandragupta I",
      "optionB":"Chandragupta II",
      "optionC":"Samudragupta",
      "optionD":"Skandagupta",
      "correctAns":"Chandragupta I"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following allowed the absorption of Tribal communities into Brahminical society?",
      "optionA":"Kushana Empire",
      "optionB":"Maurya empire",
      "optionC":"Gupta Empire",
      "optionD":"Magadha Empire",
      "correctAns":"Gupta Empire"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following text mentions that the water touched by an untouchable is seen as unfit for consumption by higher caste?",
      "optionA":"Acharakkovai",
      "optionB":"Buddhacharita",
      "optionC":"Mahabhashya",
      "optionD":"Mrichakatika",
      "correctAns":"Acharakkovai"
   },
   {
      "question":"Works of which of the following poets were also translated in many European languages?",
      "optionA":"Kalidasa",
      "optionB":"Surdasa",
      "optionC":"Shudraka",
      "optionD":"Bharavi",
      "correctAns":"Kalidasa"
   },
   {
      "question":"Halivakara refers to which of the following?",
      "optionA":"Irrigation tax",
      "optionB":"Plough tax",
      "optionC":"Crop tax",
      "optionD":"House tax",
      "correctAns":"Plough tax"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following kings faced the invasion of the Nala king Bhavadottavarman?",
      "optionA":"Narendrasena",
      "optionB":"Prithvisena I",
      "optionC":"Rudrasena II",
      "optionD":"Pravarasena II",
      "correctAns":"Narendrasena"
   }
]